所以一个容器，是一个三种不同的内核特征。
So a container, is kinda three
different kernel features put together.
其中一个就是
One of them here is,
我要说变革的根源，因为每次我讲 cha-root ，我都觉得很荒谬。
I'm gonna say change root because every
time I say cha-root, I feel ridiculous.
但我知道大多数人都这么说
But I know most people
say that as cha-root.
这就是其中的一个特点。
So that's one of the features.
下一个功能部件将是名称空间，并且
The next feature will be name spaces, and
然后，将控制 cha-root 或 c-groups。
then the feature after that will
be control cha-root or c-groups.
这三种东西结合在一起形成了一个容器。
And these kind of three things
combined together form a container.
这就是为什么我说没有一个集装箱的概念。
That's why I said there's no
one idea of a single container.
这三个东西放在一起，让你做一个容器。
It's actually these three things put
together, allow you to make a container.
好吗 ?
Okay?
那么让我们从第一个和最明显的问题开始，如果我有两个
So let's start with the first and kind of
most obvious problem, that if I have two
在同一主机操作系统上运行进程的人员。
people running processes on
the same host operating system.
我如何确保他们看不到对方的档案
How can I make sure that they
can't see each other's files.
所以如果我把我的秘密食谱下载到我的网页服务器上
So if I download like my secret
recipe unto my web server.
我不知道为什么他们的秘密菜谱在他们的网站上
I don't why has their secret
recipe on their web server.
似乎是个坏主意，但在这个例子里他们是这样做的。
Seems like a bad idea, but
in this example they do.
但我想确保没人能看到集装箱
But I wanna make sure that no one
else can see into the container.
我不希望任何一个容器里的任何人都能看到
And I don't want anyone inside of any
other container to be able to see out to
其他的
other ones.
这就是我们要用改变根或 Linux 监狱来做的事情。
So that's what we're gonna do
with change root or Linux jails.
这就是你在一个特别的过程中被称为
That's what these used to be called as
you're jailing a process to a particular
运行系统的一部分。
part of the operating system.
所以，让我们先给它一次机会。
So, let's go ahead and give it a shot.
因此，在此情况下，希望您安装 Docker 。
So, by this point hopefully
you have Docker installed.
如果没有的话，请你这样做。
If not, please do that.
我将会在 Docker内部进行这些操作。
I'm going to be doing
this all within Docker.
原因是我现在就在 MacOS上
The reason being is that,
I'm running right now on MacOS.
我的 MacOS 也没有同样的参数
And my MacOS doesn't
have the same parameters,
因为它不是 Linux 内核，对吧 ?
because it is not a Linux kernel, right?
它是一个基于 Unix 的内核， FreeBSD 之类的东西。
It's a Unix based kernel,
FreeBSD kind of stuff.
所以我将从内部开始做这些
So I'm actually going to be doing
all these examples from within
Docker 容器。
a Docker container.
所以我要在集装箱内建造集装箱
So I'm gonna be building
containers within containers,
就像容器一样，嵌套的虚拟化是人们喜欢的方法。
like containers all the way down, nested
virtualization as people like to call it.
你也能做到这一点
And you can do this too.
所以我要在这里复制这个命令
So I'm gonna copy this command right here.
我向你保证
And I promise you by
the end of this course,
你会明白这件事的具体内容
you will understand exactly what
this particular thing is doing.
但现在只要相信我这一切就好了
But for now, just trust me
that all this is gonna do is,
它会启动一个 Ubuntu 容器然后把我从里面掉进去
it's gonna start up a Ubuntu container and
then drop me inside of it.
现在，您可以使用 iTerm 来执行此操作。
Now you can do this with an iTerm.
您可以在您想要的任何仿真器中执行此操作。
You can do this within any
emulators you want to.
但在 VS 码的队伍里我要给你展示尽可能多的 VS 码
But being on the VS code team, I'm gonna
show you as much VS code as I possibly can
在他们把我赶出去之前先到这里来
get in here before they throw me out.
好的。
Okay.
我在 CSH里做这个
I'm actually doing this within CSH.
但是，这不应该对您产生零差异，您可以处于 CSH 或 bash中。
But, this shouldn't make zero difference
to you, you can be in CSH or bash.
我用螺钉试过这些命令都能起作用
I tried this in bolt and
all these commands will work both ways.
所以我又复制了，不管它在哪里。
So I copied again, wherever it was.
这里的指挥权
This command right here,
docker run- it -- name docker-host --rm -- 特权 ubuntu : 仿生。
docker run- it -- name docker-host
--rm -- privilege ubuntu : bionic.
把它粘在这里
Paste that in here.
而且它应该
And it should,
如果你还没拔起 Ubuntu Bioonic ，那么就需要第二次下载了。
if you don't already have Ubuntu Bionic
pulled, it will take a second to download.
我想它就像 150 兆字节的兆字节
I think it's like 150-ish megabytes.
我想我不记得了
It's my guess, I don't remember.
你现在可以看到我在这根树根
You can see here now,
I'm in this root at something.
所以如果你说猫的问题
So if you say cat /etc/ Issue,
会告诉你你在 Ubuntu 18.04 3 LTS
it'll tell you that you
are in Ubuntu 18.04 3 LTS.
这是个不错的诡计有时当你在容器里时
This is a nice trick,
cuz sometimes when you're in containers,
你不知道你在 Linux 中的哪个分布
you don't actually know which
distribution in Linux you're in.
这将告诉您在所有 Linux 发行版中，
This will tell you with across
all distributions of Linux which
一个你的人
one you're in.
如果您直接使用 Linux ，那么不必将其放入这样的容器中。
If you're using Linux directly, you don't
have to drop into a container like this.
您可以直接在 Linux 中直接执行此操作，与 WSL相同。
You can just do this all directly
within Linux, same thing with WSL.
如果你在 Windows 中，那么你就得在这里做同样的事。
If you're in Windows, then you're gonna
have to probably do the same thing here.
所以我要尽快把它关到我的 Windows 计算机上
So I'm gonna switch over to my
Windows computer really quick,
向你证明这其实也能从 PowerShell中实现。
just to show you that this actually
can be done as well from PowerShell.
所以我要在这儿开个酒吧
So I'm gonna open the Start bar here and
我只是想说 PowerShell 应该能打开它
I'm just gonna say PowerShell,
which should open this.
您也可以在 Windows 终端中执行此操作，您可以在 VS 代码中执行此操作。
You can also do this within Windows
Terminal, you can do this within VS Code.
我要直接从 PowerShell 应用程序中显示，因为我知道
I'm just gonna show you from the
PowerShell app directly, because I know
都是你安装的因为我们为你安装了它
all of you have it installed,
because we installed it for you.
实际上，让我们在 Windows 终端上做这个，但是
Well, let's actually do this
within the Windows Terminal, but
您现在知道 PowerShell 应用程序的位置。
you now know where the PowerShell app is.
所以我要把我复制的那个发送指令
So, I'm gonna take that send
command that I copied and
在我的麦肯公司的 Powershell 上贴着我的麦片
pasted on my Mac here in the Powershell,
and I just paste that docker run -it
--name docker-host --rm --特权ubuntu:仿生。
--name docker-host --rm
--privileged ubuntu:bionic.
如果我跑了你可以看到这里
And if I run that, you can see here.
我也在 Ubuntu
I'm in Ubuntu as well.
这将在 PowerShell 中工作。
So this will work within PowerShell.
事实上，对大部分的课程来说，这对你来说也应该是非常好的。
And actually for most of the course, this
should work pretty well for you as well.
再次，不是 PowerShell 人员，我只想向您展示，
Again, not a PowerShell person,
I just want to show you that is available,
工作的过程
that does work.
好吧我现在就回麦克
Okay, I'm gonna go back to Mac now.
回到我熟悉的电脑的舒适感
Back to the comfort of the computer
that I know much better.
再在溶液里
So again in the solutions repo,
其实我有个剧本要贯穿所有这些东西
I actually have a script that will
run through all of these things for
你，这样你就可以运行这个脚本了，它会为你运行一切。
you, so that you can just run the script
and it'll run everything for you.
但我们要用手来输入
But we're gonna type it by hand,
因为我觉得用手创作这些东西是有用的
because I think it's useful to
create these things by hand.
所以我们的目标是
So our goal here,
这样你就可以看到我现在可以看到我的整个用户系统了
so you can see I can see my entire
user system right now if I type ls.
这代表名单
Which stands for list.
我想让它让我有一个只限于一个
I wanna get it so that I have
a process that's limited to one
特定操作系统中的文件夹。
folder within my particular
operating system.
所以我要做个新目录说我的新根
So I'm gonna make a new directory and
say, my new root.
我们来吧
Let's do that.
因此 mkdir ，表示 make 目录。
So mkdir, means make directory.
因此，您可以在此处看到我的新根目录，因此
So you can see here now I have
this my-new-root directory, so
我要去我的新树根
I'm going to CD into my-new-root.
这里什么都没有
Nothing in here.
现在我需要做的第一件事是，我不能只说 " 色变 " 。
Now the first thing I need to do is I
need to, I can't just say chroot.bash.
所以你要告诉它你想把它限制在哪里，然后你告诉我
So you have to tell it where do you want
to be limited to, and then if you tell
接下来要做什么我想在里面运行一个新的外壳
what to run afterwards, whether I
wanna run a new shell inside of that.
如果我这么做就会说我不知道巴什在哪
If I do this it's gonna say,
I don't know where bash is, what is bash?
因为这里没有巴什
Because there's no bash in here.
所以你必须在这里制作一个操作系统的副本
So you actually have to make a copy of
the operating system inside of here,
因为一旦它在这里你就不会在外面打电话了
because once it's inside of here,
you won't be calling outside of it.
这真的不行
It literally can't.
所以它找不到巴什它找不到
So it can't find bash, it can't find ls,
它找不到所有通常都能得到的东西
it can't find all of these things
that would normally be available.
所以我能做到
So I can do that.
所以我可以说我要在这里看
So I can say, I'm gonna see
it out here and say copy from
bin/bash，让我们看一下，我要在我的节点里面做一个目录。
bin/bash, let's see, I have to make
a directory inside of my node.
首先我要说的是我的新菜鸟
First I'm gonna say,
mkdir inside of my-new-root/bin.
我说的是 bin/bash 的副本
And I'm saying copy from bin/bash, and
我要把它复制到我的新 root/bin/
I'm gonna copy that into my new root/bin/.
所以现在如果我说了我的新秀 / bin，酷，现在就有 bash了。
So now if I say ls my-new-root/bin,
cool, now there's bash.
我能说下我的新根
So can I say, chroot my-new-root/ bash,
我还是不知道那是什么我不明白
cuz I still don't know what
that is I don't I don't get it.
那我要怎么做
Well, what am I gonna do about that?
原来你需要有一定数量的图书馆
Well it turns out, that you need
a certain amount of libraries.
模块的库代码，这些模块
Library code of modules
that these particular
进程和命令需要运行。
processes and commands need to run.
所以如果你输入 ldd的话
So if you type ldd.
Bin/bash。
Bin/bash.
你可以在这里看到它所依赖的东西
You can see here,
here's all the stuff it depends on.
所以你得把所有东西都带上
So you need to bring
all the stuff with us.
所以我要在我的新树根里再做两个目录
So I'm gonna make another two
directories inside of my-new-root, and
我要做一个叫利库的人
I'm gonna make one called lib.
我还需要做一个叫做 " 64 " 的项目。
And I also need to make one called lib 64.
现在我可以输入我的新 lib 库 64 或者我真的很聪明
Now I could type out my new lib,
lib 64 or I can get really clever and
我可以用大撑
I can use curly brace.
我可以用逗号来说明其中一个就是叫 " 利库"
I can put a comma, which means one
of them is just gonna be called lib.
然后我再放一个这样的 64 个
And then I would put another
one called 64 like that.
所以现在我要进入我的新根
So now if I go inside of my-new-root.
你可以看到我有一个 lib 和一个 lib64
You can see I have a lib and a lib64.
只是给你一些聪明的诡计
Just some clever bash tricks for you.
你也可以输入利库然后 lib64
You can also just type out lib and
then lib64 after that,
它也能正常工作
it will work just as well.
有道理吗
Makes sense?
现在我们在这里看到了这个 ldd
So, now we've seen this ldd up here for
所以任何东西都没有路径你就可以忽略了
bash, so anything that doesn't have
a path up here you can just ignore.
但这些有路径的人
But these ones here that do have paths,
我们必须把所有这些都复制到我的新根目录里
we have to copy all of these into the
correct directories inside of my-new-root.
我想说，复制，然后我就复制并粘贴这些内容。
So I'm gonna say, copy, and
then I'm just gonna copy and paste these.
这个，复制那个。
For this one, copy that.
收到复印这个
Copy that, copy that.
我要把它复制到新的 root/lib中
And I'm gonna copy that
into my-new-root/lib.
所以现在如果我看看利库里我的新根
So now if I look inside of
my-new-root inside of the lib,
你可以看到这里有一堆我刚刚复制过来的东西
you can see here, it's got a bunch of
stuff in there that I just copied over.
现在我们还有另一只会进入 lib64
Now we got one more here,
that's gonna go into the lib64.
你可以告诉库兹我正在看他们在哪儿
You can tell cuz I'm just
looking at where they are here.
我只是在模仿同样的目录结构。
And I'm just mimicking
the same directory structure.
有道理吗
Does that make sense?
所以我要把它复制到 lib64中
So I'm gonna copy that into lib64.
所以如果你看看 lib64的内部
So now if you look inside of lib64.
我们也会明白的
We get that as well.
如果这不是显而易见的
And in case it's not obvious,
lib64 位是 64 位，而 lib 的 lib64 位是 32 位。
lib64 is for 64 bit and
the lib by implicitly would be 32 bits.
这就是流程的比特数。
Which is how many bits the processes are.
所以现在理论上我应该说
So now in theory, I should be able to say,
更改根 my-new-root/ bash。
change root my-new-root/ bash.
你看
And look.
现在我就在那个目录里面
Now, I am inside of bash,
inside of that directory.
所以我想说我不知道那是什么
So if I type ls it's gonna say,
I don't know what that is.
你什么都没有了
Cuz you don't have anything else.
有些东西只是建在 Linus 内核里，所以我可以说 pwd
Some things are just built into
the Linus kernel, so I can say pwd for
我所在的目录
what directory I'm in.
您可以看到我在此特定项目的根目录中。
You can see that I'm in the root
directory of this particular project.
我真的看不到其他的东西。
And I can't really see much else.
所以我们还是去做吧，所以也都是工作的
So, let's actually go and
make it, so ls works as well so
我们可以看到我们的目录里还有什么
we can see what else is in our directory.
因此，如果您输入退出，将会使您脱离 cha-root 环境。
So if you type exit, that'll get you
out of the cha-root environment.
这会把你送回 Ubuntu
This will drop you back into Ubuntu.
你可以在这里看到我回来了
You can see here now I'm back in this.
所以现在我要跟你说同样的事
So now I'm just gonna say the same thing
for, I'm gonna say copy /bin/ls and
那我就把它复制到我的新 root/bin 中
then I'm gonna copy that
into my-new-root/ bin.
所以现在我要把它复制到里面
So now that's gonna copy ls in there, and
I am gonna have to do the same thing for
ldd /bin/ls。
ldd /bin/ls.
一样的
Same thing.
你会发现这些都是一样的
You'll notice that a bunch
of these are the same,
我已经复制了其中的一些
that I've already copied
some of them over.
所以让我们看看 lib的内部。
So let's just look inside of lib.
你可以在这里看到我没有复制那个，所以我要复制那个。
So you can see here I haven't copied
that one, so I have to copy that one.
把那个复制到我已经拥有的那个
So copy that into,
that one I already have.
你能看到的
You can see that there.
o.2 我有那个
so.2 I have that one.
看来我也需要那个
Looks like I need that one as well.
不不不
Nope, nope.
是啊也许吧
Yes, maybe, yes.
也就是那个
So that one too.
或者你可以复制所有这些都不会造成伤害。
Or you could just copy all of them it
wouldn't do any harm either hurts.
所以这就变成了我的新版本 /lib。
So that's going into my-new-root/lib.
然后我们再看看我的新秀 / lib64
And then we'll look inside
of my-new-root/lib64.
你可以看到我要复制而不是那个
And you can see here I'm gonna
have to copy, not that one.
抱歉我来了
Sorry, there.
所以现在我可以回去把我的新根
So, now I can go back into chroot
my-new-root/ bash back in here and
理论上，我应该可以说，也找不到那个。
in theory, I should be able to say ls,
and it couldn't find that one.
所以，让我们去确保那个也在那儿，我错过了一个。
So let's go and make sure that that
one is there as well, I missed one.
就在那儿
That one right there.
很高兴告诉我这好像我找不到这个图书馆
Very nice to tell me though,
it's like I can't find this library.
把那个复制到我的新鲁特 / 利布里
So copy that one into
my-new-root/lib as well.
现在你可以看到如果我输入
And now, you can see, if I type ls,
我可以看到我的目录里面有什么。
I can actually see what's
inside of my directory.
但如果你看在 pwd 里，你可以看到它认为它是最根目录的。
But if you look inside of pwd, you can see
it thinks it's at the most root directory.
它无法摆脱这种情况，因此它没有概念。
It cannot get out of this, so
it has no concept what's going around it.
它只能看到里面。
It can only see inside of this.
它被关了，根也改了，所以叫查根
It's been jailed, or the root has
been changed, hence the name cha-root